Hugo A. Matilla Gómez

Android Developer

Address: Plaza Penuelas, 28005, Madrid Tel: 0034619037089

e-mail: hugo.matilla@gmail.com

Date of Birth: 27/01/1981 Nationality: Spanish web: matgom.com

OBJECTIVE

To be part of the development team and to contribute to with my experience in Android development, and teamwork. I feel extremely motivated to continue improving my career in Android Applications development.

MY PROJECTS

After almost four years working at Scondoo as main Android Developer and more than one year at SMF, I have been involved in many projects that are now in the Android Play Store. The duration of the developments I have worked on varied from 1 month to more than a year and were undertaken both as solo projects and in teams. I also have some experience in React Native and iOS. Some of the Android projects that can be found in the store include scondoo, HotUkDeals, reBuy, LernCoachies, and DHL.

EXPERIENCE

Android Developer scondoo Berlin/Remote. August. 2013 - Present	At scondoo, I overtook with agility and speed the code developed by 2 different agencies. This code was in several cases unstructured. Thanks to my experience I improved it with ease, not only in performance but also in design.
Ğ	Technical Skills: Android, Java, Kotlin, JSON, Git, JavaScript
Android Developer HotUKDeals Berlin. Nov. 2014 – Feb.2015	I worked remotely with the HotUKDeals team in Canada building the new generic app, where I rapidly acquired the knowledge of the software architecture and the team methodologies to help them increase their development process.
	Technical Skills: Android, Java, Clean Architecture
Android Developer Smart Mobile Factory Berlin. May. 2012 – July.2013	My ability to quickly adapt to new concepts has been used to develop and improve various Android Applications. Obstacles I must regularly overcome include definition changes, new features, improvements and tight deadlines.
_ 5 ,5 5a.,. _5	Technical Skills: Android, Java, JSON, XML, Windows Phone, Parse.
Web App & ETL Developer Innova-TSN Madrid. Jan. 2011 - Feb. 2012	I was quickly integrated into different projects, while experiencing new technical tools, supplying ideas and helping to find solutions. Additionally, I assumed managerial and technical responsibilities and regularly shared my expertise in Oracle with my colleagues.
	Technical Skills: Java, JSP, Html, CSS, Batch, C#, Oracle, Eclipse.
ETL Developer AlamoConsulting	I was part of a small team that developed a large scale corporate DataWarehouse, where versatility was a constant challenge.
Madrid. Jul. 2009 - Dec. 2010	Technical Skills: Oracle, SAS, SAS DIS

EDUCATION

Postgraduate Studies Mobile Development and Services

Universidad Nacional de Educación a Distancia

Madrid. Dec. 2010 - Jul. 2011

Main Subject Areas: Mobile Web and Android Applications development.

Minor Subject Areas: Mobile technologies, history, monetization, and IOS development.

Technical Skills: HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, Java,

Android, Objective-C, IOS.

Main Subject Areas: Programming Methodologies, Software Engineering, Computer Networks, Operating Systems, Databases, Computer Architectures,

Minor Subject Areas: Digital Systems, Microcontrollers

Programming.

Thesis: Fairness and Market Based Techniques in Wireless Sensor Networks. Grade 1.3 (TU-Berlin).

Computer Science Engineering MSc.

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Madrid. Sep. 1999 - Mar. 2009

LANGUAGES

English	TOEFL Score 94. December 2010.
German	B2 Private School.
Spanish	Mother Tongue.

I.T. SKILLS

Languages	Fluent: JAVA, Kotlin, JavaScript. Basic: Swift, Python, Haskell
WEB	Fluent: HTML5, CSS3, Nodejs. Basic: React, Meteor, Polymer, WorPress, Jekyll.
Databases	Fluent: SQLite, MongoDB, Oracle. Basic: Realm, MySQL.
Operating Systems	Fluent: OSX, Windows, Android. Basic: UNIX, iOS.
Documentation	Fluent: UML, E-R. Basic: Gantt.
Agile	Fluent: Kanban, Scrum
Version Control Systems	Fluent: Git

FURTHER INFORMATION

- Erasmus Programme: TU-Berlin 2007-2009
- Tae-Kwon-Do and Muay Thay black belt.
- Mentor at CoderDojo
- More at <u>hugomatilla.com</u>